Guide to the Henri Chopin Papers GEN MSS 868
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Henri Chopin papers
1948-2009
1960-2007
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Chopin, Henri, 1922-2008
GEN MSS 868
514
34.34 Linear Feet (90 boxes) + 9 record album storage, 31 broadside, 5 art.
The Henri Chopin Papers document the work and life of French avant-garde poet and musician Henri Chopin. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, subject files, writings relating to various publications, artwork, writings of others, photographs, audiovisual materials, and posters spanning the years 1948 to 2009.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from John Benjamins Antiquariat b.v. and Philippe Luiggi on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011 and 2013, and gift of Philippe Luigi, 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 37-53 and 72 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 54-71 and 73-80 (sound and video recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 81 and 122 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Language(s)
In French and English.
Henri Chopin (1922-2008)
Henri Chopin, primarily a French avant-garde poet and musician, but also a painter, graphic artist and designer, typographer, independent publisher, and filmmaker. He was born in Paris on June 18, 1922 and died in Dereham, England on January 3, 2008.
Chopin was a French practitioner of concrete and sound poetry and created recordings using tape recorders, various studio technologies, and the sounds of the human voice. Chopin's published works include the books Le Dernier Roman du Monde (1971), Portrait des 9 (1975), The Cosmographical Lobster (1976), Poésie Sonore Internationale (1979), Les Riches Heures de l'Alphabet (1992) and Graphpoemesmachine (2006); the magazines Cinquième Saison and OU (1958-1974); and typewriter poems, also known as dactylopoèmes.
Scope and Contents
The Henri Chopin Papers document the work and life of French avant-garde poet and musician Henri Chopin. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, subject files, writings relating to various publications, artwork, writings of others, photographs, audiovisual materials, and posters spanning the years 1948 to 2009.
Arrangement
Organized into ten series: I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1960-2004. II. Cinquième Saison and OU Files 1960-2009. III. Artwork, 1967-2006. IV. Works by Others, 1948-2006.V. Photographs, circa 1960-2000. VI. Writings, 1952-2007. VII. Audiovisual Material, 1957-2007. VIII. Posters, 1967-2006. IX. September 2013 Acquisition, 1963-2007. X. August 2015 Acquisition, 1965-1987.
TypeCollection
https://preservica.library.yale.edu/explorer/explorer.html#prop:4&c615804e-0b12-4d94-8f6c-f20012b7b3c0
Artists, France -- 20th Century; Concrete poetry, French -- 20th Century; Design -- 20th Century; French poetry -- 20th Century; Graphic arts -- 20th Century; Musicians -- France -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, French -- 20th Century -- Archives; Publishing -- 20th Century; Sound poetry, French -- 20th Century; Printing; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Drawings (visual works); Photographs; Posters; Realia; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Musicians -- France -- 20th Century; Poets -- France -- 20th Century; Chopin, Henri, 1922-2008
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1960-2004; 1; 154992; 6 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The first run of correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. The second run of correspondence is arranged by the correspondents' country of origin and other subjects. Filed at the end of the series is various correspondence not included with the others.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of files of correspondence and other material shedding light on Chopin's development as an artist.
  - "A" General, 1978-1993, undated; 155394 (Box 1)
  - Aquaviva, Frédéric, 2001-2007, undated; 155393 (Box 1)
  - Albert-Birot, Arlette, 1969-2000, undated; 155392 (Box 1)
  - Anseeuw, Alain, 1973, undated; 155391 (Box 1)
  - "B" General, 1972-2008, undated; 155390 (Box 1)
  - Buhler, Rosine, 1992-1996; 155389 (Box 1)
  - Bedou, Dominique, 1979 February- July; 155388 (Box 1)
  - Bekri, Tahar, 1993, undated; 155387 (Box 1)
  - Benhamou, Stéphane, 1977-1985; 155386 (Box 1)
  - Blank, Jeremy, 1985-1986; 155385 (Box 1)
  - Bobillot, Jean-Pierre, 1995, undated; 155384 (Box 1)
  - Boussand, Juliette, 1992-1995; 155383 (Box 1)
  - Brindeau, Serge & Paule, 1974-1986; 155382 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Jean, 1972-1986; 155381 (Box 1)
  - Buck, Paul, 1977-1978; 155380 (Box 1)
  - Bulatov, Dmitry, undated; 155379 (Box 1)
  - "C" General, 1975-2008, undated; 155378 (Box 1)
  - Cernotto, Andrea, 1992-1994, undated; 155377 (Box 1)
  - Charbonnier, Georges, 1973-1988, undated; 155376 (Box 1)
  - Charette, Marin de, 2003-2004, undated; 155375 (Box 1)
  - "D" General, 1974-2007, undated; 155374 (Box 1)
  - De Smet, Bernard, 1969, undated; 155373 (Box 1)
  - "E" General, 1978-2005; 155372 (Box 1)
  - "F" General, 1984-2007, undated; 155371 (Box 1)
  - "G" General, 1968-2004, undated; 155370 (Box 1)
  - Gentils, René, 1976-1977; 155369 (Box 1)
  - Gherban, Alexandre, 1989-1998, undated; 155368 (Box 1)
  - "H" General, 1976-1998, undated; 155367 (Box 1)
  - Herrero-Ducloux, Abel, 1988; 155366 (Box 1)
  - Hetten, Claude, 1983-1993, undated; 155365 (Box 1)
  - Hubert, Judd & Renée Riese, 1993-2002, undated; 155364 (Box 1)
  - Hudak, John, 1987-1994, undated; 155363 (Box 1)
  - "J" General, 1982-2004; 155362 (Box 2)
  - Jandl, Ernst, 1977-1981; 155361 (Box 2)
  - Jani, Sylvie, 1985-1989; 155360 (Box 2)
  - Jegou, Alain, 2005-2007; 155359 (Box 2)
  - "K" General, 1972-2004, undated; 155358 (Box 2)
  - Kahn, Carole, 1993-2007; 155357 (Box 2)
  - Kahn, Douglas, 1988, undated; 155356 (Box 2)
  - Kelter, Christina, 1996-2002; 155355 (Box 2)
  - Kolodny, Frank, 1979-1980; 155354 (Box 2)
  - "L" General, 1967-1992, undated; 155353 (Box 2)
  - Leclerc, Daniel, 1997-2005; 155352 (Box 2)
  - Linhartová, Věra, 1975-1976; 155351 (Box 2)
  - Lurie, Toby, 1978-1981; 155350 (Box 2)
  - "M" General, 1972-2002, undated; 155349 (Box 2)
  - Mairey, Françoise, 1975, undated; 155348 (Box 2)
  - McAlpine, Alistair, 1974-1981; 155347 (Box 2)
    Includes photocopies of letters from Henri Chopin to Raoul Hausman, 1963-1971
  - Mercher-Brousse, Henri, 1972-1973; 155346 (Box 2)
  - Métail, Michèle, 1975-2006, undated; 155345 (Box 2)
  - Miskin, Lionel, 1967, undated; 155344 (Box 2)
  - "N" General, 1991-1996, undated; 155343 (Box 2)
  - Nadau, Jean-Pierre, undated; 155342 (Box 2)
  - Nakov, Andrei Boris, 1973-1974, undated; 155341 (Box 2)
  - Nordin, Ingvar Loco, 1994-1995; 155340 (Box 2)
  - Nuaud, Jean-Pierre, 1993-1995, undated; 155339 (Box 2)
  - "O" General, 1972-1992, undated; 155338 (Box 2)
  - "P" General, 1972-2000, undated; 155337 (Box 2)
  - Palermo, Fiorenzo, 2006 February-September; 155336 (Box 2)
  - Pestana, Silvestre, 1979-1982, undated; 155335 (Box 2)
  - Peynaud, Claude, 2001-2003; 155334 (Box 2)
  - Plantier, Thérèse, 1971-1987; 155333 (Box 2)
  - Power, Kevin C., undated; 155332 (Box 2)
  - Prévot, Marthe, 1972-1980, undated; 155331 (Box 2)
  - "R" General, 1972-2003, undated; 155330 (Box 2)
  - Rushton, Anthony P., undated; 155329 (Box 2)
  - "S" General, 1973-2001, undated; 155328 (Box 2)
  - Scholz, Christian, 1973-1995; 155327 (Box 2)
  - Sorin, Raphaël, 1973-1980, undated; 155326 (Box 2)
  - Sulzbach, Renée, 1973-1977; 155325 (Box 2)
  - "T" General, 1969-1996, undated; 155324 (Box 3)
  - Trouvé, Henri, 1974-1987, undated; 155323 (Box 3)
  - Trowell, Stephen G., 1974-2000, undated; 155322 (Box 3)
  - "U" General, 1973-1978; 155321 (Box 3)
  - "V" General, 1968-1992; 155320 (Box 3)
  - Vince, John, 1970-1971; 155319 (Box 3)
  - "W" General, 1968-1991, undated; 155318 (Box 3)
  - "Z" General, 1976-1992; 155317 (Box 3)
  - Zweig, Ellen, 1983-1985, undated; 155316 (Box 3)
  - Students, 1990-2002, undated; 155315 (Box 3)
  - United Kingdom, 155296
    - Cities & Universities, circa 1969-2004; 155314 (Box 3)
    - Festival Ingatestone, 1969; 155313 (Box 3)
    - University of Manchester, 1972-1977; 155312 (Box 3)
    - O'Connor, Michael, 1974, undated; 155311 (Box 3)
    - Galleries & Publishers, circa 1969-2004; 155310 (Box 3)
    - Gaberbocchus Press Limited, 1974-1975; 155309 (Box 3)
    - Arts Council of Great Britain, 1972-1978; 155308 (Box 3)
    - The Birmingham Arts Laboratory Ltd., 1972-1973; 155307 (Box 3)
    - Eastern Arts Association, 1972-1979, undated; 155306 (Box 3)
    - Ilkley Literature Festival, 1978-1979, undated; 155305 (Box 3)
    - Carrell, Christofer, 1970-1984; 155304 (Box 3)
    - Finch, Peter, 1975-1979, undated; 155303 (Box 3)
    - Furnival, John & Astrid, 1983-2006, undated; 155302 (Box 3)
    - Leonard, Tom & Hughson, Joan, 1977-1987, undated; 155301 (Box 3)
    - Reichardt, Jasia, 1965-1999, undated; 155300 (Box 4)
    - Richardson, Robert, 1979-2003, undated; 155299 (Box 4)
    - Tabor, Richard, 1973-1993, undated; 155298 (Box 4)
    - Vonna-Michell, Erik, 1979-1990, undated; 155297 (Box 4)
  - Italy, 155279
    - Cities & Universities, 1967-1994, undated; 155295 (Box 4)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1968-1993, undated; 155294 (Box 4)
    - Bellora, Gianfranco, 1975-1987, undated; 155293 (Box 4)
    - Bertola, Carla & Vitacchio, Alberto, 1987-2004, undated; 155292 (Box 4)
    - Bertozzi, Gabriele-Aldo, 1988-1993; 155291 (Box 4)
    - Bonotto, Luigi, 1992-2006; 155290 (Box 4)
    - Caignard, Rolland, 1996-2003; 155289 (Box 4)
    - Carcano, Emanuele, 1995-1998, undated; 155288 (Box 4)
    - Conz, Francesco, 1968-2007, undated; 155287 (Box 4)
    - Fontana, Giovanni, 1980-2007, undated; 155286 (Box 4)
    - Nannucci, Mauritio, 1967-1995; 155285 (Box 4)
    - Minarelli, Enzo, 1982-2004, undated; 155284 (Box 4)
    - Morghen, Gianni, 2007, undated; 155283 (Box 4)
    - Studio Morra, 1979-2006, undated; 155282 (Box 4)
    - Sarenco, 1972-1996, undated; 155281 (Box 4)
    - Schwarz, Arturo, 1976-1979; 155280 (Box 5)
  - Belgium, 155267
    - Cities & Universities, 1963-1998; 155278 (Box 5)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1979-2003, undated; 155277 (Box 5)
    - Atelier de Création Sonore Radiophonique, 2003-2004, undated; 155276 (Box 5)
    - Instituut voor Psychoacustica en Elektronische Muziek, Gent, 1976-1991; 155275 (Box 5)
    - MAC's Grand-Hornu, 2005-2006; 155274 (Box 5)
    - Dachy, Marc, 1973-1977; 155273 (Box 5)
    - Édeline, Francis, 1972-2007; 155272 (Box 5)
    - De Maere, Jan, 1976-1978; 155271 (Box 5)
    - Schraenen, Guy, 1973-1994; 155270 (Box 5)
    - Sotiaux, Daniel, 1979-1989; 155269 (Box 5)
    - Van der Hoeven, Jan, 1981-1984; 155268 (Box 5)
  - United States of America, 155260
    - Cities & Universities, 1972-2005; 155266 (Box 5)
    - White, Erdmute Wenzel, 1972-1985; 155265 (Box 5)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1965-1993, undated; 155264 (Box 5)
    - Kostelanets, Richard, 1976-1985; 155263 (Box 5)
    - Rothenberg, Jerome, 1978-1996; 155262 (Box 5)
    - The Ruth & Marvin Sackner Archive, 1971-2005; 155261 (Box 5)
  - Canada, 155253
    - Cities & Universities, 1974-2006, undated; 155259 (Box 5)
    - The 11th International Festival of Sound Poetry, 1978; 155258 (Box 5)
    - Le Lieu: Centre en Art Actuel, 1986-2007; 155257 (Box 5)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1973-1978; 155256 (Box 5)
    - Beaulieu, Simone, 1989-1990; 155255 (Box 5)
    - Vie Des Arts, 1968-1980; 155254 (Box 6)
  - Austria, 155249
    - Cities & Universities, 1983-1995; 155252 (Box 6)
    - Schule für Dichtung in Wien, 1985-2007; 155251 (Box 6)
    - Jaschke, Gerhard, 1984-1991; 155250 (Box 6)
  - Switzerland, 155241
    - Cities & Universities, 1973-2003; 155248 (Box 6)
    - Galleries & Publishers, circa 1979-1992; 155247 (Box 6)
    - Aaron, Richard, 1972-1974; 155246 (Box 6)
    - Adler, Marcel, 1972-1979; 155245 (Box 6)
    - Armleder, John M., 1973-1977; 155244 (Box 6)
    - Barras, Vincent, 1988-2005; 155243 (Box 6)
    - Lagarde, François, 1975-1985; 155242 (Box 6)
  - Sweden, 155236
    - Swedish Embassy, London, 1978 December 12; 155240 (Box 6)
    - Centre Culturel Suédois, 1979-1991; 155239 (Box 6)
    - Malmö Konsthall, 1977-1978; 155238 (Box 6)
    - Fylkingen, 1969-1977; 155237 (Box 6)
  - The Netherlands, 155228
    - Cities & Universities, 1968-1993; 155235 (Box 6)
    - Landy, Leigh, 1981-1993; 155234 (Box 6)
    - Stedelijk Museum, 1974-1985; 155233 (Box 6)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1968-2007; 155232 (Box 6)
    - Ruhé, Harry, 1980-1984; 155231 (Box 6)
    - Van Toorn, Jan, 1980-2000; 155230 (Box 6)
    - De Waard, Frans, 1994-1997; 155229 (Box 6)
  - Germany, 155217
    - Cities & Universities, 1989-1995, undated; 155227 (Box 6)
    - Literaturwerkstatt Berlin, 2003; 155226 (Box 6)
    - Bielefelder Colloquium Neue Poesie, 1985-1995; 155225 (Box 6)
    - Universität Gesamthochschule Siegen, 1981-1992; 155224 (Box 6)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1968-2006, undated; 155223 (Box 6)
    - Archiv Sohm, 1969-1983; 155222 (Box 6)
    - Breger, Udo, 1972; 155221 (Box 6)
    - Dana, Llys, 1994-2007; 155220 (Box 6)
    - Hundertmark, Armin, 1975-2002; 155219 (Box 7)
    - S Press Tonbandverlag, 1973-1997; 155218 (Box 7)
  - South America, 155215
    - Cities & Universities, 1973-1993; 155216 (Box 7)
  - Australia, 155212
    - Cities & Universities, 1969-1992; 155214 (Box 7)
    - Contemporary Sound Arts, 1992-1993; 155213 (Box 7)
  - Denmark, 155210
    - Cities & Universities, 1978-1984; 155211 (Box 7)
  - Spain, 155206
    - Cities & Universities, 1975-1997; 155209 (Box 7)
    - Galeria Sephira, 1991-1992; 155208 (Box 7)
    - Cinca, Javier, 1988-1989; 155207 (Box 7)
  - Greece, 155204
    - Cities & Universities, 1987-1991; 155205 (Box 7)
  - Israel, 155202
    - Shelef, Zvi, 1987 May-June; 155203 (Box 7)
  - Japan, 155199
    - Kouhei & Akiko, 2004-2005; 155201 (Box 7)
    - Shimoda, Seiji, 1993-1995; 155200 (Box 7)
  - Poland, 155194
    - Cities & Universities, 1978-1986; 155198 (Box 7)
    - The International Drawing Triennial, Wrocław, 1978-1982; 155197 (Box 7)
    - Kostołowski, Andrzej, 1973-1976; 155196 (Box 7)
    - Galeria Akumulatory 2, 1974; 155195 (Box 7)
  - Portugal, 155192
    - Cities & Universities, 1976-1996; 155193 (Box 7)
  - Czech Republic, 155188
    - Cities & Universities, 1967-1998; 155191 (Box 7)
    - Bienále Užité Grafiky, Brno, 1969-1974; 155190 (Box 7)
    - Dilia, 1969-1970; 155189 (Box 7)
  - TV - Radio - Magazines, 155167
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1968-1988; 155187 (Box 7)
    - Saarländischer Rundfunk, 1976 March 4; 155186 (Box 7)
    - Telefilm Saar GmbH, 1976-1977; 155185 (Box 7)
    - Westdeutscher Rundfunk, 1972-1997; 155184 (Box 7)
    - Esser, Nina, 2005-2006; 155183 (Box 7)
    - Lenz, Michael, 1996; 155182 (Box 7)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1968-1984; 155181 (Box 7)
    - Australian Broadcasting Coproration, 1983-1997; 155180 (Box 7)
    - Radiodiffusion-Télévision Belge, undated; 155179 (Box 7)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1968-1995; 155178 (Box 7)
    - Magazines, 1976-2001; 155177 (Box 7)
    - Radio France, 1977-1995; 155176 (Box 7)
    - France Culture, 1980-1993; 155175 (Box 7)
    - Encyclopaedia Universalis, 1988-1995; 155174 (Box 7)
    - Sveriges Radio, 1969-1989; 155173 (Box 7)
    - Sveriges Riksradio AB, 1991-1994; 155172 (Box 7)
    - Télévision Suisse Romande, 1963-1975; 155171 (Box 7)
    - Radio Lausanne, 1963 November 26; 155170 (Box 8)
    - KCMU, Seattle, 1993-1994; 155169 (Box 8)
    - KPFA, Berkeley, 1972-1983; 155168 (Box 8)
  - Press releases, circa 1961-1963; 155166 (Box 8)
  - France, 155117
    - Officials, 1977-1993; 155165 (Box 8)
    - Actions pour Promouvoir le Français des Affaires, 1991-2005; 155164 (Box 8)
    - Société des Gens de Lettres de France, 1976-1988; 155163 (Box 8)
    - Société Civile des Auteurs Multimedia, 1982-2004; 155162 (Box 8)
    - Monnaie de Paris, 1986-2000; 155161 (Box 8)
    - Ministère de L'Education Nationale et de la Culture, 1964-1965; 155160 (Box 8)
    - Présidence de la Republique, 1982-1985; 155159 (Box 8)
    - Ministère de la Culture, 1964-1996; 155158 (Box 8)
    - Centre national des arts plastiques, 1985 June 28; 155157 (Box 8)
    - Bibliothèque nationale de France, 1989-2006; 155156 (Box 8)
    - Cabinet des Estampes, 1994-1995; 155155 (Box 8)
    - Imprimerie nationale, 1989 May-June; 155154 (Box 8)
    - Estampes et photos, 1990-2003; 155153 (Box 8)
    - Centre Georges Pompidou, 1974-2001; 155152 (Box 8)
    - Institut de Recherche et Coordination Acoustique/Musique, 1994, undated; 155151 (Box 8)
    - Cities & Universities, 1995-2000; 155150 (Box 8)
    - Bioulès, Vincent, 1981-1994; 155149 (Box 9)
    - Bibliothèque Municipale, Amiens, 1991-1993; 155148 (Box 9)
    - Bourges, 1979-1994; 155147 (Box 9)
    - Ville de Clermont Ferrand, 1995-1997; 155146 (Box 9)
    - Grenoble, 1996-2004; 155145 (Box 9)
    - Maison de la Culture du Havre, 1975-1980; 155144 (Box 9)
    - Université de Nantes, 1985-1992; 155143 (Box 9)
    - Ville de Nîmes, 1980-1982; 155142 (Box 9)
    - Musées de Marseilles, 1992-1993; 155141 (Box 9)
    - Festival Expoésie, Périgueux, 2005-2006; 155140 (Box 9)
    - Toulouse, 1982-2001; 155139 (Box 9)
    - Galleries & Publishers, 1989-2006; 155138 (Box 9)
    - Arnaudet, Didier, 1980-1981; 155137 (Box 9)
    - Barrière, Françoise, 1975-2005; 155136 (Box 9)
    - Galerie Convergence, Nantes, 1987-2000; 155135 (Box 9)
    - Beurard, Patrick, 1984-1985; 155134 (Box 9)
    - Collet, Michel & Verhaeghe, Valentine, 1995-2006; 155133 (Box 9)
    - Duchêne, Gérard, 1977-1994, undated; 155132 (Box 9)
    - Ensemble Vide, 1987-1989; 155131 (Box 9)
    - Féray, Marie-Laure & Serge, 1993-2008, undated; 155130 (Box 9)
    - Tartalacrème, 1980-1992; 155129 (Box 9)
    - Librairie-galerie sel du marchand, 1989-1991; 155128 (Box 9)
    - Hubaut, Joël, 1987-1997, undated; 155127 (Box 9)
    - Hurtado, Eric & Marc, 1995 January 25; 155126 (Box 9)
    - Malartre, André, 1991-1993; 155125 (Box 9)
    - Mathieu, Didier, 1991-2006; 155124 (Box 9)
    - Meier, Richard, 1989-2005, undated; 155123 (Box 9)
    - Montessuis, Joachim, 1994-2005; 155122 (Box 9)
    - Metamkine, 1995-2003; 155121 (Box 9)
    - Tyson, Matthew, 1984-1995, undated; 155120 (Box 9)
    - Schwartz, Paul, 1981-1994, undated; 155119 (Box 9)
    - Foundation Danae, 1986; 155118 (Box 10)
  - Paris, 155095
    - Publishers & Galleries, 1979-2006; 155116 (Box 10)
    - Lucken, Christopher, 1996-1998, undated; 155115 (Box 10)
    - Debon, Claude, 1994 July-November; 155114 (Box 10)
    - Galleries & Booksellers, 1971-1995, undated; 155113 (Box 10)
    - Publishers, 1967-2001, undated; 155112 (Box 10)
    - Bory, Jean-François, 1970-1971; 155111 (Box 10)
    - Canorel, Franck, 1995; 155110 (Box 10)
    - Delaunay, Philippe, 2006-2007; 155109 (Box 10)
    - Dufeu, Antoine, 2003-2007; 155108 (Box 10)
    - Giroud, Michel, 1975-1987; 155107 (Box 10)
    - Lebel, Jean-Jacques, 1979-1990, undated; 155106 (Box 10)
    - Lemaire, Gérard-Georges, 1975-1993, undated; 155105 (Box 10)
    - Orta, Jorge, 1998-2000; 155104 (Box 10)
    - Place, Jean-Michel, 1976-2007, undated; 155103 (Box 10)
    - Petithory, Jean & Chantal, 1972-1989, undated; 155102 (Box 10)
    - Restany, Pierre, 1976, undated; 155101 (Box 10)
    - Roulet, Jean-Claude, 1982-1992; 155100 (Box 10)
    - Sabaté Bériain, Hélios, 1981-2006; 155099 (Box 10)
    - Saillard, Martine, 1998-2005; 155098 (Box 10)
    - Sauvagnac, Nicole, 1980-1985, undated; 155097 (Box 10)
    - Vernier, Marc, 2001-2006; 155096 (Box 10)
  - Artists, 155017
    - Aeschbacher, Arthur, 1977-1983; 155094 (Box 10)
    - Aguirre, Javier, 1969-1982; 155093 (Box 10)
    - Arp, Jean & Marguerite, 1964 March-May; 155092 (Box 10)
    - Arcand, Pierre-André, 1989-2002, undated; 155091 (Box 10)
    - Autrand, Charles, 1968-1971; 155090 (Box 10)
    - Ball, Hugo, 1976 July 25; 155089 (Box 10)
    - Grögerová, Bohumila & Hiršal, Josef, 1965-1990, undated; 155088 (Box 11)
    - Balpe, Jean-Pierre, 1976-1994; 155087 (Box 11)
    - Battier, Marc, 1984-1993, undated; 155086 (Box 11)
    - Bergner, Marcus, 1993, undated; 155085 (Box 11)
    - Bosseur, Jean-Yves, 1977-1984; 155084 (Box 11)
    - Boussand, Marcel, 1971-1995, undated; 155083 (Box 11)
    - Brunson, Bill, 1975-1977; 155082 (Box 11)
    - Burke, Herbert, 1974-1984; 155081 (Box 11)
    - Cage, John, 1984 September 25; 155080 (Box 11)
    - Crozier, Robin, 1971 October-November; 155079 (Box 11)
    - Curtay, Jean-Paul, circa 1979-1989; 155078 (Box 11)
    - Darras, Jacques, 1982-1996; 155077 (Box 11)
    - Donguy, Jacques, 1986-2007; 155076 (Box 11)
    - Dutton, Paul, 1983-2002; 155075 (Box 11)
    - Ferrando, Bartolomé, 1991-2002, undated; 155074 (Box 11)
    - Godard, Maxime, 1993 May-July; 155073 (Box 11)
    - Gonçalves, Olga, 1976 January-February, undated; 155072 (Box 11)
    - Greenham, Lily, 1978-1979, undated; 155071 (Box 11)
    - Gruber, Jacques, 1973, undated; 155070 (Box 11)
    - Henry, Maurice, 1969 June 5; 155069 (Box 11)
    - Herel, Petr, 1983-1999, undated; 155068 (Box 11)
    - Higgins, Dick, 1975-1997, undated; 155067 (Box 11)
    - Hublin, Serge, 1978 May-July; 155066 (Box 11)
    - Jappe, Elisabeth, 1992-1993; 155065 (Box 11)
    - Kaplan, Philip, 1969-1985, undated; 155064 (Box 11)
    - Kemp, Penny, undated; 155063 (Box 11)
    - Kern, Bliem W., 1977-1981; 155062 (Box 11)
    - Keppler, Joseph, 1983-1990, undated; 155061 (Box 11)
    - Kroupa, Adolf, 1969-1973; 155060 (Box 11)
    - Kucharz, Lawrence, 1978-1979, undated; 155059 (Box 11)
    - Lafabrie, Bernard-Gabriel, 1991-1992, undated; 155058 (Box 11)
    - Laszlo, Jean-Noël, 1989-2007; 155057 (Box 11)
    - Latal, Georges, 1969-1990; 155056 (Box 11)
    - Artists, 1971-1999, undated; 155055 (Box 12)
    - Mallin, Rupert, 1979; 155054 (Box 12)
    - Mikriammos, Philippe, 1975-1977; 155053 (Box 12)
    - Miller, David, 1975-1977; 155052 (Box 12)
    - Miranda, Fatima, 1993-2006, undated; 155051 (Box 12)
    - Mon, Franz, 1976-1981; 155050 (Box 12)
    - Noël, Christophe, 1990-1992; 155049 (Box 12)
    - Özkök, Lütfi, 1970-1993, undated; 155048 (Box 12)
    - Parant, Jean-Luc, 1987-2005; 155047 (Box 12)
    - Pénard, Rémy, 1993-2004; 155046 (Box 12)
    - Pétronio, Arthur, 1976-1979, undated; 155045 (Box 12)
    - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard), 1964-1977, undated; 155044 (Box 12)
    - Pisek, Bruno, 1995-2005; 155043 (Box 12)
    - Pont, Gérard, 1983 March-October; 155042 (Box 12)
    - Pooley, Hugh, 1975-1976, undated; 155041 (Box 12)
    - Popper, Frank, 1968-1982; 155040 (Box 12)
    - Proïa, François, 1990-1993, undated; 155039 (Box 12)
    - Raïna, 1977, undated; 155038 (Box 12)
    - Ramos, Jose Miguel, 1974-1976, undated; 155037 (Box 12)
    - Restany, Pierre, 1986-1990; 155036 (Box 12)
    - Richter, Hans, 1974-1977; 155035 (Box 12)
    - Rougier, Vincent, 1989-2005, undated; 155034 (Box 12)
    - Roussel, Alain, undated; 155033 (Box 12)
    - Rühm, Gerhard, 1981-1987; 155032 (Box 12)
    - Ruppenthal, Steve, 1972-1979, undated; 155031 (Box 12)
    - Saint Helm, 1960-1985; 155030 (Box 12)
    - Scherstjanoi, Valerie, 1991-2003; 155029 (Box 12)
    - Smadja, Alex, undated; 155028 (Box 12)
    - Sondzia, Joseph, 1971-1979; 155027 (Box 12)
    - Strange, Allen, 1978-1980, undated; 155026 (Box 12)
    - Viallat, 1981 January-February; 155025 (Box 12)
    - De Vree, Freddy, 1978, undated; 155024 (Box 12)
    - Wendt, Larry, 1978-2003; 155023 (Box 12)
    - Williams, Emmett, 1987 January-May; 155022 (Box 12)
    - Wilmański, Tomasz, 1986-1991, undated; 155021 (Box 12)
    - Xenakis, Constantin, undated; 155020 (Box 12)